What did you eat?
You had rations for two weeks.
You were inside
for nearly four months.
I don't remember eating.
How long did you think
you were inside?
Days.
Maybe weeks.
What happened to Josie Radek?
- I don't know.
- What about Sheppard?
Thorensen?
Dead.
Ventress?
I don't know.
Then what do you know?
This is a cell.
Like all cells,
it is born
from an existing cell.
And by extension,
all cells were ultimately
born from one cell.
A single organism
alone on Planet Earth,
perhaps alone in the universe.
About four billion years ago
One became two. Two became four.
Then eight, 16, 32.
The rhythm of the dividing pair,
which becomes
the structure of every microbe,
blade of grass, sea creature,
land creature,
and human.
The structure
of everything that lives
and everything that dies.
As students of medicine,
as the doctors of tomorrow,
this is where you come in.
The cell we're looking at
is from a tumor.
Female patient, early thirties,
taken from the cervix.
Over the course
of the next term,
we will be closely examining
cancer cells in vitro
and discussing
autophagic activity.
Professor?
Hi, Katie.
I read the John Sulston
paper last night.
I still feel I'm not working
hard enough.
I'm behind the other students,
they find everything easier.
You aren't,
and they don't, okay?
Lena!
Dan.
I've been looking
for you at lunch,
but you never seem to be around.
I've been catching up
on some writing.
All work and no play. It's...
Not healthy.
I wanted to ask,
do you have plans Saturday?
Sarah and I have
a few people over.
A garden party
while the weather holds.
Actually, I do have plans.
I think it'll be a lot of fun.
Thanks, Dan,
I really appreciate it,
but I'm going
to paint our bed...
The bedroom.
It's been a year, Lena.
You're allowed
to come to a barbecue.
It is not a betrayal
or an insult to his memory.
I'm gonna paint the bedroom.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
I thought you were gone
forever.
Kane?
No one knew anything
about your unit.
I contacted everyone.
Everyone I could.
The other partners knew
just as little as me.
Was it covert?
Maybe.
What's that mean, "Maybe"?
Okay, yeah. It was covert,
yeah, I think so.
Pakistan again?
I don't know where it was,
or what it was.
How is that possible?
Was... Was it warm?
Was there snow?
Did the people there
speak Portuguese,
or Swahili, or Pashto?
How long have you been back?
I don't know.
How'd you get back?
What base did you fly into?
I don't know.
What about the rest
of your unit?
Did they come back with you?
You must be able
to tell me something.
You vanished off the face
of the Earth for 12 months.
I deserve a better explanation
than no explanation.
Does it matter?
Kane,
how did you get home?
I was outside.
Outside the house?
No.
No, I was outside the room.
The room with the bed.
The door was open,
and I saw you.
I recognized you.
Your face.
I don't feel very well.
Stay with me, baby.
I'm right here with you.
Male, 31, hemorrhage,
in seizure.
Stay with me, baby. I love you.
Baby, look at me.
Can you do something?
You call for a police escort?
Easy, easy!
- Out of the truck now!
- Out!
- What are you doing?
- Move! Out, out!
- Don't shoot!
- Out, out, out!
- What is going on?
- Do not move!
- What are you doing?
You can't move him.
Let him go! Let him go!
Let him go!
You must be feeling dreadful.
It's a hangover from
the sedative you were given.
Come on, sit down.
Who are you?
My name is Dr. Ventress.
I'm a psychologist.
Why am I talking
to a psychologist?
Am I in a psychiatric hospital?
- No.
- Then what?
Where am I?
Where's my husband?
You served in the military
for seven years.
I'm a professor
from Johns Hopkins.
I want to know what the fuck
I'm doing here.
You r research area
is the genetically programed
life cycle of a cell.
Where is my husband?
Yeah, I'd like to talk
about Sergeant Kane.
When did he arrive back home?
I want to see a lawyer.
You're not gonna be able
to see a lawyer.
Did he explain how he got back?
No.
Did he contact you at any
point while he was away?
No.
What did he tell you about
his mission when he returned?
Nothing.
What about before he left?
Did he ever mention
where he was going,
what he was doing?
He never said, I never asked.
But you made regular requests
for information from his unit CO
until six months ago,
and then you stopped.
Why was that?
Thought he was dead?
Time to move on?
It's not easy to move on.
I didn't.
I'm done answering questions.
It's your turn.
Your husband's here.
He's extremely ill.
- In what way?
- Multiple organ failure.
Massive internal bleeding.
He must have been exposed
to some sort of radiation,
some kind of virus.
You have to tell me
where he was,
what he was doing.
I could actually help him.
A religious event?
An extraterrestrial event?
A higher dimension?
We have many theories.
Few facts.
It started around
three years ago.
Blackwater National Park
reported that a lighthouse
was surrounded
by something they termed
a "Shimmer."
One of the wardens
went in to investigate.
Never returned.
The event was classified.
Since then, we've approached
by land, by sea,
sent in drones, animals,
and teams of people.
But nothing comes back.
And the boundary's getting
bigger, it's expanding.
So far, it's eating into
barely populated swampland,
which we evacuated
under the pretext
of a chemical spill,
but that won't last much longer.
In a few months,
the area will have grown
to where we are right now.
And then we're talking cities,
states,
and so on.
You say nothing comes back.
But something has.
Yes.
He's dying.
We need to come to an agreement
about what to do with you.
You're not going
to let me go home?
Is that what you want?
To go home?
No.
I want to be with him.
You're not talking to me.
Sorry.
Zoned out.
Thinking about the next mission?
No.
I was just looking at the moon.
It's always so weird seeing it
like that in the daylight.
Like God made a mistake.
Left the hall lights on.
God doesn't make mistakes.
That's somewhat key to
the whole being-a-god thing.
Pretty sure He does.
You know He's listening
right now, don't you?
You take a cell,
circumvent the Hayflick limit,
you can prevent senescence.
I was about to make
the exact same point.
It means the cell
doesn't grow old,
it becomes immortal.
Keeps dividing, doesn't die.
We see aging
as a natural process,
but it's actually
a fault in our genes.
I get really turned on
when you patronize me.
It's really hot.
Without it, I could keep
looking like this forever.
Okay, well, that could
constitute a mistake.
You didn't tell me where
you're heading this time.
I know there's something
strange about this mission.
Why?
The silence around it
is louder than usual.
Kind of angling for a clue here.
So...
We'll be under
the same hemisphere.
What does that tell me?
It tells you that if you
step outside and you look up,
we'll be looking
at the same stars.
Holy fucking shit.
- What?
- Are you kidding?
What?
You think that's what I do
while you're away?
What?
You think I'm out in the garden,
pining, looking up at the sky?
Shut up.
Oh, to think my beloved Kane...
All right. Okay.
...is looking
at this selfsame moon.
Stop it.
Oh, my distant celestial friend...
No, no!
Please care
for my brave soldier.
Jesus! You know what? You are
disrespectful, seriously.
Not only to your former
comrades in the armed forces,
but also to the President.
You forgot the flag.
I'm getting
to the motherfucking flag.
Oh, my hero!
- Screw you.
- Okay.
She's all by herself.
Don't you think
we should make friends?
Well, obviously you should.
Yep, I'll do it.
Hey.
- Am I intruding?
- No, not at all.
Cool.
You know,
always see you here alone.
I'm guessing you probably feel
weird or awkward.
Somewhat, I guess.
Don't. Seriously, don't.
The people here put themselves
to sleep in the fetal position,
making cooing noises.
It's freaky, you know.
I'm Anya.
Lena.
- Nice to meet you.
- You, too.
Why don't you come
and meet my crew?
Come make friends. Come on.
Ladies, meet Lena.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
Yeah, that's Cassie Sheppard
and Josie Radek.
- Hi.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
Do you want to have a seat?
Thank you.
So, first day
at the Southern Reach.
Yes.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You all been here a long time?
Yeah, right from the start.
I'm a geomorphologist.
I've been testing the magnetic
fields around the boundary.
Which is like using confetti
to test a hurricane.
And I've been here
10 months? Ten months!
Paramedic from Chicago.
Tried to join an NGO, but
my application got flagged,
so Southern Reach got me.
Only two months.
I'm a physicist.
I came straight from
my Cambridge post-doc.
She's very smart.
What's your story, Lena?
I'm from Johns Hopkins.
Biologist.
- There you go.
- Biologist?
- Told you she was smart.
- What?
We had a bet on your profession,
and Josie had "biologist,"
of course.
- I had "law enforcement."
- I had you as single.
Jesus! Do you have to hit on
everyone, like all the time?
Come on. Fuck that.
Under the circumstances,
I think I'm allowed to roll
the dice a few more times.
Under what circumstances?
Well, yeah, crazy as it seems...
Crazy as it is.
We are headed that way.
You're going into the Shimmer?
Six days and counting.
- You three?
- Four.
Ventress.
Dr. Ventress?
Team leader.
- All women.
- Scientists.
The previous teams have been
largely military, so yeah.
What do you think
happened to them?
Well, there are two theories
of what went wrong
in the Shimmer.
One, something kills them.
Two, they go crazy
and kill each other.
There was one military
guy who made it out.
Yeah.
Sergeant.
Yeah, but you heard about
the state that he was in.
Kane,
I know why you went in.
I am so sorry.
And I know what I have to do.
So, you didn't tell
them about your connection
to Sergeant Kane.
I thought
it would complicate things.
What?
What would it complicate?
Why are you going
into the Shimmer?
The mission statement is to
reach the supposed source of
the Shimmer, the lighthouse.
Enter, acquire data, and return.
But I don't think that
that's your mission statement.
No.
I've been watching the
phenomenon for a while now.
I profile the volunteers.
I pick the teams.
They enter. I watch.
I watch it grow closer.
There's only so long
one can do that.
But you need to know
what's inside?
Yes. I do.
So do I.
So that's the complication.
You want to come with us.
I can't do anything
for him here.
Soldier-scientist.
You can fight. You can learn.
You can save him.
You requested to join
the mission.
You knew all
other missions had failed,
and the only survivor
was barely surviving.
That was a brave choice.
Lowed him.
I'm only trying to understand
what drove you.
Lowed him.
So I went in.
And then we get some real meals.
Spaghetti. Here's Radek's
vegetable crackers.
Cornbread. That's not so bad.
You're finally awake.
Got to give me a second.
I'm a little disoriented.
Join the club.
You don't remember
setting up camp, do you?
I don't remember anything
after we reached the tree line.
None of us do.
And we did a food inventory.
From the depletion, it looks
like we've been out here for
at least three or four days.
That's not possible.
That's what I said.
Guys, I've been checking
my comms and nav equipment.
They boot up fine, no problem
with the electronics,
and the camera is working,
but anything that sends
a signal out of the Shimmer
is down.
Even though we've probably
got about 20 satellites
above us right now.
And check this out.
So we have got
no compass, no comms,
no coordinates,
and no landmarks.
Well, we know
we're in the state park.
We head south, hit the ocean,
then just follow the shoreline
until we hit the perimeter wall.
Right?
How do we know what's south?
Come on, Josie, you know this.
Hour hand at the sun.
Split the difference between
the hour hand and 12.
South.
Good. We're oriented.
We weren't really expecting
the comms equipment to work,
were we?
I mean, there's been
three years of expeditions
and three years
of radio silence.
Let's pack up and get moving.
We've already lost
a lot of the day.
I'm gonna check this out.
Get us out of this damn swamp.
All right.
Let's check out the hut.
Looks like someone's about
to have a wedding.
These are very strange.
Why?
They're all so different.
To look at them,
you wouldn't say
that they're the same species.
But they're growing from
the same branch structure.
So it has to be
the same species.
It's the same plant.
It's like they're stuck
in a continuous mutation.
A pathology?
Yeah, well,
you'd sure as hell
call it a pathology
if you saw this in a human.
Jackpot
Sheppard.
Mode of transportation.
Anything interesting in there?
No. It's been long abandoned,
maybe even before...
Radek?
Radek!
- Radek!
- It's got my bag!
Radek!
Something's got my bag!
It's got my bag!
- Josie, what's happening?
- What's going on?
Grab my shoulder!
Get her. Come on.
I got her!
You're good. You're good.
Okay.
Let's sit you down.
Help me with her bag.
Okay, just breathe.
It's okay, you're just fine.
- What the hell happened?
- Something in the water.
Get up! Get up! Go.
Shit! Get back.
Sheppard!
Sheppard, watch out!
Holy fuck!
It's exactly the same
as the flowers.
Look at the teeth.
Concentric rows.
Something here is making giant
waves in the gene pool.
Sharks have teeth like that,
don't they?
Do you think it's a crossbreed?
You can't crossbreed
between different species.
Lena, this is getting heavy.
The mutations
were subtle at first.
More extreme as we grew
closer to the lighthouse.
Corruptions of form.
Duplicates of form.
Duplicates?
Echoes.
Is it possible
these were hallucinations?
I wondered that myself.
But they were shared
among all of us.
It was dreamlike.
Nightmarish?
Not always.
Sometimes it was beautiful.
You hurt?
It's just a bruise.
Must have gotten that
from the gator.
Yeah.
So, where'd you learn to shoot?
I was in the military
before I was an academic.
Marines?
Army. Seven years.
Feels like a lifetime ago now.
Yeah.
All other lives
feel like a lifetime ago.
We were kids, I was married.
Which do you carry
around your neck?
A husband or a child?
Husband.
He was in the Army, too.
That's... That's how we met.
"Was" in the Army? He quit?
K.l.A.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Guess there had to be something.
What do you mean?
Volunteering for this.
It's not exactly something
you do if your life is in
perfect harmony.
We're all damaged goods here.
Anya is sober,
therefore an addict.
And Josie wears long sleeves
because she doesn't
want you to see
the scars on her forearms.
She's tried to kill herself?
No, I think the opposite.
Trying to feel alive.
Ventress?
Yeah. As far as anyone knows,
no friends, no family,
no partner, no children.
No concession in her at all.
You'?
I also lost someone.
Not a husband, though.
A daughter. Leukemia.
God, I'm sorry.
In a way, it's two bereavements.
My beautiful girl
and the person I once was.
Hey, hey.
We got something here.
This used to be the headquarters
of the Southern Reach
before the Shimmer swallowed it.
More mutations.
They're everywhere.
Malignant.
Like tumors.
Is that the old mess hall?
Yeah.
Let's billet there. Come on.
There's beds and bags.
You think people are here?
Were here.
Yeah, I'm gonna go
with the past tense.
Damn.
Shit.
This shit is heavy.
Can't carry this.
Lena, what you got going on?
Guys, check this out.
Peyton. Mayer.
Kane. Shelley.
Those were the soldiers
on the last expedition.
Looks like they
were using this room
as their base of operations.
Why are some of the names
crossed out?
Let's not jump to conclusions.
I don't know, maybe we should.
Yeah.
This is a plan-view
of the base, right?
Yep. This is the mess hall.
- That's the building we're in?
- Yep.
I think that the times
by the names
are a guard rota,
so if they were guarding the
perimeter, we should, too.
- Copy that.
- Yep.
This might be able
to tell us something.
"For those that follow."
I believe that means us.
Memory card.
I should be able to play this.
It's working.
All right?
- Okay?
- Okay.
Okay.
- Okay. Okay. Okay.
- Okay.
Ready? Okay.
Shit.
What is he doing?
No, stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop.
Hold him. Hold him down.
There. There.
Okay. So we know what happened
to the last group,
they went insane.
There was something
alive inside that man.
No, that was a trick
of the light.
What?
I've been a paramedic
for 10 years. All right?
I've scraped people
off the side of the road.
You see some weird shit.
That was a trick of the light.
His insides were moving.
No, it was shock, Radek.
That was a shock response.
Watch it again.
No, I'm not gonna
fucking watch it again!
That was not intestines.
It was like a worm.
Okay, then you
watch it, Sheppard!
Where are you going?
- Where'd she go?
- Just ahead.
What is it?
I don't know.
I don't want
to stay here tonight.
We don't have a choice.
- Please.
- Come on.
It's too late in the day
for us to move on.
Come on, let's go outside.
That's nice of you.
Why aren't you here?
I got to leave a day early.
What?
Wait, today?
- Right now.
- Shit.
But we had a whole day planned.
We were gonna drive
to the country.
- We can't.
- Can you at least...
"Now" means right now?
Yeah.
What is it?
I do
love you,
Lena.
I love you, too.
Hey.
The mystery unraveling?
Something's unraveling.
I think you're doing okay.
Look, Josie's getting some rest.
Yeah.
With the help
of a little sedative.
How about you? Get some sleep?
Some.
I'm at least
as freaked as Josie.
I'm just hiding it better.
I should check on Ventress.
Yep.
What are you doing up?
You're not supposed
to relieve me until 3:00.
I'm done sleeping for the night.
Okay.
Come look at this.
Okay, this is where we are,
and that's the lighthouse.
Southwest is Ville Perdu.
It's a small community
we evacuated two years ago.
I think we should
head there tomorrow,
and then head out for the coast
the following morning.
Good.
You Okay?
I was gonna say, when
you didn't tell the team
about your connection to Kane,
I wasn't sure
if that was a good idea.
But after seeing that footage,
yeah...
I'm not sure how they would
have reacted to you.
Why did my husband volunteer
for a suicide mission?
Is that what you think
we're doing?
Committing suicide?
You must have profiled him,
you must have assessed him.
He must have said something.
So you're asking me
as a psychologist?
Yeah.
Then as a psychologist,
I'd say you're confusing
suicide with self-destruction.
Almost none of us commit suicide
and almost all of us
self-destruct.
In some way,
in some part of our lives.
We drink, or we smoke.
We destabilize the good job
or the happy marriage.
But these aren't decisions,
they're...
They're impulses.
In fact,
you're probably better equipped
- to explain this than I am.
- What does that mean?
You're a biologist.
Isn't self-destruction
coded into us?
Programed into each cell?
What was that?
Don't know.
Josie, wake up.
Wake up, Josie, come on.
Wake up.
Something's happening.
- Do you see anything?
- No.
What happened? I heard a noise.
What?
Something's come through
the fence.
Through the fence?
It's ripped open
like a fucking zipper.
- I can't see anything.
- Yeah, neither can I.
Sheppard!
- Fuck.
- What's going on?
Sheppard was just next to me,
and something took her.
Fuck! Fuck!
- Sheppard!
- Shit.
Help me!
Sheppard!
We have to go back.
We have to go back now.
She's right.
Right? In what sense?
We've been attacked twice.
We lost one of our own.
We have evidence
the previous team
went nuts and chopped
each other up.
I really don't know how much
more right she has to be.
We haven't reached
the lighthouse.
We still don't
understand the cause
or the nature of the Shimmer.
We have data,
observations, photographs.
She has hella footage.
All of which
makes the phenomenon
less explicable, not more.
I'm gonna get to the lighthouse.
And I'm fine going on my own.
You just need to decide
whether you're coming
with me or not.
It's like she doesn't even
notice that Sheppard is dead.
She's crazy.
She's a crazy old bitch.
And thanks for
the fucking backup, Lena!
I didn't realize
there were sides.
Yeah.
Yeah, there are sides.
Okay. Then I agree with you,
we should go back.
Good. Okay, great. There we go.
Okay, so the three of us
- can just pack up our...
- Hold on a minute.
Hold on. We should go back, yes.
But it took us, what,
six days to get here?
And the coast is two days away.
And as Sheppard said,
when we get to the coast,
we can just follow it until
we hit the perimeter wall.
You're saying that we get out
by going deeper in?
Yeah, if you like. Yeah.
"Like"?
No, I don't fucking "like."
This isn't some bullshit tactic
to get us to the lighthouse,
is it?
This is not about
the lighthouse, okay?
I believe that the coast
is the best route out.
Okay?
You lied to them.
I didn't know
what going back meant.
Why it would be safer
than going forward.
You didn't know,
but you made the decision
to continue as if you did.
Ventress made the decision.
Ventress had cancer,
she was never coming back.
You knew she was sick.
I had guessed.
And you wanted to continue?
Yes.
I did.
She could still be alive.
It's highly doubtful.
We need to know.
Go.
Fine.
I'm coming with you.
I'll go alone.
Did you find her?
Yeah.
She's dead.
You Okay?
Fine.
Just leave me the fuck alone.
We'll camp here tonight.
It's another two hours' walk
up the coast.
They've grown this way.
That doesn't make any sense.
I think it does.
At first, I thought
the radio waves
were blocked by the Shimmer,
and that's why no one
inside could communicate
with base or GPS.
But the light waves
aren't blocked,
they're refracted. And...
It's the same with the radios.
Signals aren't gone.
They're scrambled.
That leaf in your hand.
Do you know what you'd get
if you sequenced it?
What?
- Human Hox genes.
- "Hox"? What does "Hox" mean?
They're the genes
that define the body plan,
the physical structure.
And the plants
have human body plan.
Arms attached to shoulders,
legs to hips.
It's literally not possible.
It's literally what's happening.
The Shimmer is a prism,
but it refracts everything.
Not just light and radio waves.
Animal DNA. Plant DNA.
All DNA.
What do you mean, all DNA?
She's talking about our DNA.
She's talking about us.
All right.
I guess this is the bedroom.
Let's secure doors and windows.
This was a mistake.
Okay.
You spend more time away from
your husband than with him.
You can't talk to him
about work,
and he won't talk
to you about his.
And there is a clear physical
and intellectual connection
between us.
Have I covered the bases?
You forgot to mention your wife.
I love my wife.
She's blameless in this.
Come on, Lena.
What's really going on here?
You think that something
may have happened to him?
Or you think he knows.
That's it, isn't it?
You think somehow he's found
out about our affair.
Has he found out?
Yes.
You should go.
- No, Lena, I...
- Dan.
I'm not interested in talking,
or anything you have to say.
Just get dressed and get out.
You know, it's not me you hate.
It's yourself.
No, Dan, it's you, too.
It's never gonna happen again.
You lying bitch!
- What's going on?
- No.
You don't get to ask
that fucking question.
You answer it!
Brother.
Boyfriend.
Husband.
Why didn't you tell us?
You knew.
Obviously.
Did you know?
Okay.
So, there are two theories
of what went wrong
in the Shimmer.
One is that something in here
killed them. Two
is that they went crazy
and they killed each other.
Josie nearly got killed
by an alligator,
and Cass did get killed
by a bear.
So, yes, theory one, it fits.
But
I didn't actually see a bear.
And neither did Josie.
The only people who saw a bear
were Lena and Ventress.
So nothing's confirmed.
Everything's on their word.
Everything's on Lena's word.
And what we know now...
What we know
is that Lena is a liar.
Shut the fuck up!
Lena, you're a liar.
Did you kill Cass?
Did you lose your shit?
Or do you think
that I've lost my shit,
and now we're just gonna
fuck each other up?
That's theory two.
When I look at my hands
and my fingerprints,
I can see them moving.
If I let you go
and you tie me to a chair
and cut me open,
are my insides gonna move
like my fingerprints?
But I'm not the one
tied to a chair.
You are.
Help me!
Cass?
You said she was dead.
Cass! Cass, I'm coming!
Cass, is that you?
Help me!
Help...
Don't react.
...me!
Help...
Help me.
What are you doing?
- I'm leaving.
- Now?
- It's not even light yet.
- I don't have time to wait.
We are disintegrating!
Our bodies as fast as
our minds. Can't you feel it?
It's like the onset of dementia.
If I don't reach
the lighthouse soon,
the person
that started this journey
won't be the person
that ends it.
I want to be the one
We should go, Josie.
How long was your husband
in the Shimmer?
It's hard to say, exactly.
Theoretically,
as long as a year.
That's a long time to be
inside and remain intact.
I'm not so sure he was intact.
I'm right
about the refractions, aren't I?
Yeah.
I checked my blood last night.
It's in me.
It will be in all of us.
It was so strange hearing
Sheppard's voice
in the mouth
of that creature last night.
I think, as she was dying,
part of her mind became
part of the creature
that was killing her.
Imagine dying frightened
and in pain
and having that as the only
part of you which survives.
I wouldn't like that at all.
Ventress wants to face it.
You want to fight it.
But I don't think I want
either of those things.
Josie?
Josie.
One by one, all gone,
except you.
How do you explain that?
Is it something
I need to explain?
Yes, you do.
I had to come back.
I'm not sure any of them did.
Hey.
I thought I was a man.
I had a life.
People called me Kane.
And now I'm not so sure.
If I wasn't Kane, what was I?
Was I you?
Were you me?
My flesh moves like liquid.
My mind is
just cut loose.
I can't bear it.
You ever seen
a phosphorus grenade go off?
They're kinda bright.
Shield your eyes.
If you ever get out of here,
you find Lena.
I will.
No.
Five, four, three, two...
It's the last phase.
Vanished into havoc.
Unfathomable mind.
And now beacon.
Now sea.
Dr. Ventress?
Lena?
We spoke.
What was it we said?
That I needed to know
what was inside the lighthouse.
That moment's passed.
It's inside me now.
What's inside you?
It's not like us.
It's unlike us.
I don't know what it wants.
Or if it wants.
But it will grow
until it encompasses everything.
Our bodies and our minds
will be fragmented
into their smallest parts
until not one part remains.
Annihilation.
So it was alien.
Can you describe its form?
No.
Was it carbon-based or...
I don't know.
What did it want?
I don't think
it wanted anything.
But it... It attacked you.
It mirrored me.
I attacked it.
I'm not sure it even knew
I was there.
It came here for a reason.
It was mutating our environment.
It was destroying everything.
It wasn't destroying.
It was changing everything.
It was making something new.
Making what?
I don't know.
A team reached the lighthouse
a few hours ago.
Everything is ash.
If what you encountered
was once alive,
it seems it's now dead.
Now will you tell me
what happened to my husband?
When the Shimmer disappeared,
his blood pressure stabilized
and his pulse rate
started to rise.
A few hours later,
he was not only awake,
he was lucid.
He's still in isolation,
obviously.
So am I.
You aren't Kane.
Are you?
I don't think so.
Are you Lena?